<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/code/pfs.css"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>The Earl Marshals order touching the habits of the peeresses at the coronation of Their Majesties King VVilliam and Queen Mary</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 4KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 2 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2016-02">2016-02 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">B21530</idno><idno type="EEBO-CITATION">18767248</idno>
  <idno type="VID">205250</idno>
  <idno type="EEBO-PROQUEST">2240850561</idno>
  
            <idno type="STC">Wing E70</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">18767248</idno>
            <availability><p>This keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above is co-owned by the
    institutions providing financial support to the Early English Books Online Text Creation
    Partnership. This text is available for reuse, according to the terms of <ref target="https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/"> Creative Commons 0 1.0 Universal
    licence</ref>. The text can be copied, modified, distributed and performed, even for commercial
    purposes, all without asking permission.</p></availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt><relatedItem type="facs" target="https://data.historicaltexts.jisc.ac.uk/view?pubId=eebo-e"/>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. B21530)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 205250)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 1650:14)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>The Earl Marshals order touching the habits of the peeresses at the coronation of Their Majesties King VVilliam and Queen Mary</title>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>1 sheet ([2] p.)   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed by Edw. Jones,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>In the Savoy [London] :</pubPlace>
                  <date>MDCLXXXVIII [1688]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in the British Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,363 texts created during Phase 1 of the project have been released into the public domain as of 1 January 2015. Anyone can now take and use these texts for their own purposes, but we respectfully request that due credit and attribution is given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Full documentation of the original data capture process is available from the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.
   All versions of the texts are now archived and freely available for download. See <ref target="https://textcreationpartnership.org/faq/#faq05">the TCP Download FAQ</ref>
   for detailed information. The TEI P5 versions are also freely available from the <ref target="https://github.com/textcreationpartnership">TCP Github repository</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp" matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)" replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term type="personal_name">William --  III, --  King of England, 1650-1702 --  Coronation.</term>
               <term type="personal_name">Mary --  II, --  Queen of England, 1662-1694 --  Coronation.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2013-12 </date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-12 </date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo </label>Sampled and proofread </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-12 </date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited </change>
         <change>
            <date>2015-03 </date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion </change>
      <change><date>2021-05 </date><label>lb</label>TEI P5 conversion </change></revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb facs="tcp:205250:1"/>
            <head>THE Earl Marshals Order TOUCHING THE HABITS of the PEERESSES AT THE CORONATION <hi>Of Their Majesties King <hi>VVILLIAM</hi> And Queen <hi>MARY.</hi>
               </hi>
            </head>
            <p>
               <seg rend="decorInit">T</seg>HAT the Robe or Mantle of a <hi>Baro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ness</hi> be of Crimson Velvet, the Cape to be Furr'd, and Powder'd with two Bars or Rowes of Ermine, the said Mantle to be Edged round with Me<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>niver unpowder'd, two Inches in breadth, and the Train to be three Foot on the Ground.</p>
            <p>The Coronet to be with six Pearls upon the Rim, not rais'd upon Points.</p>
            <p>That the Robe or Mantle of a <hi>Vicountess</hi> be like that of a <hi>Baroness,</hi> only the Cape Powder'd, with two Rowes and a half of Ermine, and the Train to be three Foot and nine Inches long on the Ground.</p>
            <p>The Coronet to be a Rim or Circle with Pearls, 16 in number, not raised upon Points.</p>
            <p>That the Mantle or Robe of a <hi>Countess</hi> be like that of a <hi>Baroness,</hi> only the Cape is to be Powder'd, with three Rowes of Ermine, the Edging three Inches broad, and the Train a Yard and half long on the Ground.</p>
            <p>The Coronet to be compos'd of eight Pearls rais'd upon Points or Rays, with small Leaves between above the Rim.</p>
            <p>The Mantle or Robe of a <hi>Marchioness</hi> to be the same as that of a <hi>Baroness,</hi> only the Cape to be Powder'd with three Rowes and a half of Ermine, the Edging four Inches broad, the Train a Yard and three quarters on the Ground.</p>
            <pb facs="tcp:205250:2"/>
            <p>The Coronet to be compos'd of four Leaves and four Pearls rais'd upon Points of Equal height as the Leaves alternately above the Rim.</p>
            <p>The Mantle or Robe of a <hi>Duchess</hi> the same as that of a <hi>Baroness,</hi> the Cape to be Powder'd, with four Rowes of Ermine, the Edging five Inches broad, and the Train two Yards on the Ground.</p>
            <p>The Coronet to be compos'd of eight Leaves all of Equal height above the Rim.</p>
            <p>The Surcoats or Kirtles to be all of Crimson Velvet, close Bodied and clasp'd before, Edg'd or Bordered with Meniver pure, two Inches broad, and Scallop'd down the Sides from below the Girdle, and slop'd away into a Train proportiona<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble to the respective Train of the Robe for each degree <hi>(viz.)</hi> a Third part thereof.</p>
            <p>The Sleeves of the Surcoats to be also of Crimson Velvet, Scallop'd at the Bottom, edg'd with Meniver pure, and fring'd with Gold or Silver. The Caps of their Coronets to be all of Crimson Velvet, turned up with Ermine, with a Button and Tassel of Gold or Silver on the Top, suitable to the Fringe of their Sleeves.</p>
            <p>Lastly, the Peticoats to be of Cloth of Silver, or any other White Stuff, either Laced or Embroydered, according to every ones Fancy.</p>
            <p>The Mantles to hang back, being fasten'd to each Shoul<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der with Cordons of Silver or Gold, suitable to their Fringe, with Tassels of the same hanging one on each side down to the Waste.</p>
            <p>The Surcoats or Kirtles to be open before that the Peti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>coats may appear.</p>
            <p>☞ <hi>Note, That not any of the Coronets, of any of the Ranks beforementioned, are to be Set with Stones or Jewels.</hi>
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
      <back>
         <div type="license">
            <p>I do Appoint <hi>Edward Jones</hi> to Print this Order,</p>
            <closer>
               <signed>
                  <list>
                     <item>
                        <hi>NORFOLKE,</hi> and</item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>MARSHAL.</hi>
                     </item>
                  </list>
               </signed>
            </closer>
         </div>
         <div type="colophon">
            <p>In the SAVOY <hi>Printed by</hi> Edw. Jones, <hi>MDCLXXXVIII.</hi>
            </p>
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>